Mwendwa John.

+254706299339 | mwendwajohn65@gmail.com

PROFFESIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated and customer-focused software developer with a successful background in leading highly performing teams to meet and exceed objectives. A tactical and inspiring team builder with experience in training, team development, and delivering excellence.

Skilled software developer with deep knowledge of Web development and exceptional proficiency in HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Java script, PHP and Laravel programming language, currently learning React. Expert ability to meet specific customer requirements by developing, optimizing, and reworking systems.

SKILLS

- Project organization.
- Budget and cost analysis.
- End-user support.
- Confidential data management.
- Hardware installations.

- Data collection and analysis.
- Problem-solving skills.
- Company policy adherence.
- Contract Management

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Attachment | February 2022 – May 2022

Techducate Africa, Nairobi

- Wrote effective and concise testing reports of software.
- Testing and evaluating new programs.
- Deploying software tools, processes, and metrics.
- Training users.
- Working closely with other developers, UX designers, business and systems analysts

Software Developer Intern | February 2021 – April 2021

IEN Africa, Nairobi

- Researching, designing, implementing, and managing software programs.
- Writing and implementing efficient code.
- Determining operational practicality.
- Working closely with other developers, UX designers, business and systems analysts.
- Maintaining and upgrading existing systems.

TESTER | Sep 2019 - August 2021

Utest, Nairobi

- Completed consistent manual tests of test cases and updated results.
- Documented software issues.
- Used Agile and Scrum methods to complete project milestones within deadlines.
- Successfully detected bugs and defaults in computer software and provided developers with details of what was discovered.

EDUCATION

 EXPECTED IN 11/2021 Bachelor of Science Software Development. | Information Technology.

KCA University, Nairobi, Kenya.

2014 TO 2017 Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education.
 Chesamisi High School, Kimilili, Kenya.

LINKS

Check out my profile on LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mwendwa-john-26bb75190

 My certificates: https://drive.google.com/open?id=10y0_dXfNZfzR5JfqJ0ms7Sehul3UCSj0_

REFERENCES

Mr. Madara Earnest.

Lecturer at KCA university.

earnestmadara@gmail.com

+254722892206.